Guide to the Stanford University, Women's Recreation Association, Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Women's Recreation Association, records
1902-1975
SC0141
Stanford University. Women's Recreation Association.
8 Linear feet
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfer, Dept. of Athletics, Physical Education and Recreation, 1975.
Information about Access
None.
Historical Note
The Women's Athletic Association (WAA) was organized in 1893, changing its name to the Women's Recreation Association (WRA) in 1955.
Scope and Content
Records include administrative files and correspondence (primarily 1950-1970); minutes (1902-1969); activities records, affiliations material and scrapbooks (1920- 1970); and photographs, banners, ribbons and markers. The scrapbooks contain clippings, photographs, programs, brochures, and lists. Of note are the materials on La Fiesta Lagunita of 1924 and 1926 which include scripts and drawings of sets and costume designs.
Access Terms
Orchesis (Stanford University); Stanford University -- General subdivision--Students.;; Stanford University. Women's Recreation Association. -- General subdivision--History.;; Sports for women.; Women athletes.
Collection Contents
- Administration, Series 1
  - ASSU constitution, 1963-64 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Advisor, 1963-64 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Brochures, Directories, 1956-75 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Budgets, 1934-68 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Budgets, 1960-70 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Budgets, 1965-71 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Budgets - Account Book, 1909-23 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Budgets - Account Book, 1958-59, 1960-62 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Budgets - Accounts, 1950-69 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Budgets - Deposit slips and statements, 1969-70 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Budgets -Insurance and outstanding P.O.'s, 1963-70 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Budgets -Statements, 1966-68 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Calendars, Quarterlies and Summer Calendars, 1955-68 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Constitution - WAA, WRA (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Freshman Activities, 1968-70 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Handbooks, Miscellaneous handouts (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Mailing lists, 1960-65 and n.d. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Overseas campuses, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Policies, 1957-65 and n.d. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - President's Report, 1934/35, 1935/36 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - President's Report, 1949/50-1952/53 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - President's Report, 1956/57-1963/64 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - President's Report, 1964/65 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - President's Report, 1965/66-1967/68; 1970/71 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Reports - miscellaneous, 1930-71 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Reports - Secretary, Treasurer, Publicity Chairman, 1953-68 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Treasurer's notebook, 1959-66 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Minutes, Series 2
  - Board, 1946-48 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Executive Committee, 1956-57 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - 1902-1910 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - 1910-1918 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - 1919-1926 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - 1926-1935 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - 1934-1941 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - 1944-1946 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 1948-1954 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 1948-1958 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 1959/60 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 1963/64 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 1964/65 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - 1965/66 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - 1967/68 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - 1968/69 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, Series 3
  - 1938-1939 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - 1940-1943 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - 1943-1944 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - 1945-1946 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - 1946-1947 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - 1947-1949 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - 1949-1950 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - 1950-1951 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - 1951-1952 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - 1952-1953 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - 1953-1954 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - 1954-1955 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - 1955-1956 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - 1956-1957 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - 1957-1958 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - 1960-1961 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - 1963-1964 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - 1964-1965 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - 1969-1973 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Activities, Series 4
  - Archery, 1920-66 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Badminton, 1941-66 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Baseball, 1935-36 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Basketball, 1921-75 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Bowling, 1944-74 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Dance, 1974-75 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Dance - Fiesta, 1924 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Dance - La Fiesta Lagunita, 1924, 1926 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Dance - Folk, 1943-67 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Dance - Orchesis, 1941-66 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Equitation, 1928-61 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Fencing, 1934-67 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Golf, 1932-69 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Hockey, 1923-74 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Hockey - U.S. Field Hockey Association, 1934-52 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Ice Skating, 1960-62 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Inner tube Water Polo, 1974-75 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Intramurals, 1941-68 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Rifle Team, 1929-66 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Ski Club (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Softball, 1950s (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Swimming, 1941-71 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Table Tennis, 1964-75 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Tennis, 1919-69 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Tournaments - general information, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Track, 1922-29 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Volleyball, 1955-68 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Affiliations - Area, State, National, Series 5
  - Bay Area Colleges and Universities - Sportsday Association, 1959-66 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Bay Area Colleges and Universities - Sportsday Planning Meetings, 1956-68 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Bay Area Sports Days, 1950s-60s (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Bay Area Sports Day, Nov. 17, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Bay Area Sports Day, Nov. 16, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Bay Area Sports Day, Nov. 14, 1964; Nov. 16, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Triangular Sports Day [Stanford, Mills, California], 1919-52 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - CAFCW [California Athletic Federation of College Women], Constitution, 1946-52 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - CAFCW - Conferences, 1940-61 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - PSRARFCW [Pacific Southwest Regional Athletic and Recreation Federation of College Women], 1961-68 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - AFCW [Athletic Federation of College Women], 1926-51 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - AFCW, 1954-68 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - AFCW, Annual Report of Executive Secretary-Treasurer to Faculty Advisory Committee, 1953/54 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - AFCW, Annual Report of Executive Secretary-Treasurer to Faculty Advisory Committee, 1954-55 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - AFCW, Report of State Conferences, 1946, 1954, 1956 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - AFCW, Convention Report, 1953 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - ARFCW [Athletic and Recreation Federation of College Women - succeeded the AFCW in 1957], conferences, 1939-65 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - AFCW Sportlight, 1935-45 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - AFCW Sportlight, 1947-57 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - AFCW Sportlight, 1957-65 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - AFCW and others, older records, 1920-53 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - National Joint Committee on Extramural Sports, 1959-61 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - NAAF [National Amateur Athletic Federation], 1924-39 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous Material, Series 6
  - Photographs, 1930-60s and n.d. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Ribbons, banners, markers (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Scrapbook, 1927-30 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1930-38 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook, 1939-47 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook, including photographs, 1920s (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, including photographs, 1930s (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, including photographs, 1940s (Box 15, Folder 2)
- Additional Records, Series 7
  - Insurance and publicity, 1959-68 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Bay Area Planning, 1956-69 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Bay Areas Sports Day, Nov. 14, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Bay Areas Sports Day, Nov. 5, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 4)